JIE-REN (JARRON) SHIH

jarronshih@gmail.com 1-408-505-6800

As a 6-year experience developer, infrastructure builder, and security consultant, Jie-Ren Shih is experienced in building secure, scalability, and high availability enterprise product. With experience of hosting container-based and serverless web service on AWS, he is an expert in DevOps process from developing, testing, opertaion, and monitoring modern web service. Jie-Ren is also familiar with cloud related technologies including AWS, kubernetes, docker, and serverless architecture.

SKILLS

Programing Python, Javascript, C/C++, HTML/CSS,

DevOps Docker, Jenkins, CI/CD, Monitor/Alert, Unittest,

Cloud Skills AWS, ECS, Kubernetes, Docker Swarm, SaaS sytem design, Scalable sytem design,

Linux System Boot process, Encryption driver, Network programming,

EMPLOYMENT

Staff Software Developer, Trend Micro

2017-01 — Present

Design and implement SaaS service running in cloud platform with container orchestration. Targeting for automatically CI/CD and high test coverage.

- As Full Cycle Developers doing design, develop and operate container-based services from company data center to AWS for SaaS.
- Build up operation, monitor alert and dashboard report using automated script from scratch.
 Introduce asynchronous on Python to enhance process and I/O usage with 60% improvement.
- Legacy code remodeled: Python 2 to 3, built up unittest and integration test from scratch (0% to over 90%).
- Separate data streaming part from monolithic application to embrace serviceless framework.

Senior Software Developer, Trend Micro

2015-01 - 2016-12

In network defense group, responsible for CI/CD, network traffic parsing and hosting a Sandbox SaaS service.

- Introduce CI/CD best practice to the product, as the standard of the following project.
- Enhance SaaS service to support multi-tenancy customers sharing resource in the cloud to reduce cost.
- Parsing network traffic in packet level, work as data engineer in network analysis product.

Software Developer, Trend Micro

2012-09 — 2014-12

In Cloud Storage Encryption Product Team, responsible for development boot device encryption feature and Linux software agents on cloud service platform.

- Implement boot disk encryption feature to prevent boot data leakage on Windows and variant Linux distributions, including Ubunto, CentOS, RHEL, AmazonLinux and SUSE.
- Design software on major cloud service providers including Amazon EC2, Microsoft Azure and HP-Cloud.
- 2013 Q2 Trend Engineer of Quarter.

EDUCATION

National Taiwan University

Foundation of Cryptography, Artificial Intelligence, Parallel and Distribution Computing, 2010-09 - 2012-07

National Taiwan University

First Prize in NTUEE Undergraduate Outstanding Project. 2006-09 - 2010-07

WRITING

[Patent] Root Volume Encryption Mechanism in Para-virtualized Virtual Machine, Trend Micro Achieve root volume encryption in a para-virtualized virtual machine 2015

MIFARE Classic: Practical Attacks and Defenses, Chinese Cryptology and Information Security Association

2013

Securing M2M with Post-quantum Public-key Cryptography, Emerging and Selected Topics in Circuits and Systems / IEEE Journal

2013

A practical experience with RFID security, Mobile Data Management: Systems, Services and Middleware, 2009 / IEEE

2009

RECOGNITION

Certified ScrumMaster, Scrum Alliance

2015 2013 Q2 Engineer of Quarter, Trend Micro

2013

INTERESTS

Contract Bridge

Current Current

Board Game